Samantha Pendleton MSc

PhD Student in Clinical Informatics Data Science Masters | Business IT Graduate

samanfapc@gmail.com

BIRMINGHAM UK



github.com/sap218



twitter.com/sap218

Profile

Currently a PhD student in Clinical Informatics. I have an extensive set of skills and experience, ranging from data science applications, bioinformatics, and clinical analysis. I am an organised individual, who works well through fast-paced environments, and able to communicate effectively with colleagues. I have experience in assisting individuals, specifically students, throughout my employment and educational practises.

Skills

Using Python and R, I have a wide set of skills: machine learning, unsupervised clustering, text mining, statistics, natural language processing, ontologies, semantics, sentiment analysis.

Education

- PhD student in Clinical Informatics (2018-present)
 Institute of Cancer and Genomic Sciences, University of Birmingham
 Thesis: Creating an AI based data assistant to bridge genotype to metadata linking primary clinical data to biobank sample
- » Masters graduate in Data Science (2017-18)
 Institute of Maths, Physics, and Computer Science, Aberystwyth University
 Dissertation: Metagenomics of Acid Soil
- » Bachelors graduate in Business Information Technology (2014-17)
 Institute of Maths, Physics, and Computer Science, Aberystwyth University
 Dissertation: Web Major Project

Experience

- Researcher, Bioinformatics; Aberystwyth University (2017)
 An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data
- Assistant; Information Services at Hugh Owen Library, Aberystwyth University (2016-17)
 Jobs: Assisted staff, attended focus groups, made strategy & floor plans
- » Student worker;
 - Teaching assistant for Computational Biology; Worklink, University of Birmingham (2019)
 - Advisor/Demonstrator; AberWorks, Aberystwyth University (2016-18)
- » Volunteering (2006-17)
 - Jobs: Environmental work, assisted with charity events

 Peer mentor for the Computer Science Department at Aberystwyth University

Achievements

- » Images of Research entry (2020)
- » Max Perutz Science Writing Award entry (2019)
- » BCS Lovelace Colloquium attendee (2017-18)
- » President of Computer Science Society, Aberystwyth University (2017)
- » Certificates from Aberystwyth University (2016) Diversity & Manual Handling Course

Publications / Tools

- » The Ocular Immune-Mediated Inflammatory Diseases Ontology (2021) https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104542
- » Jabberwocky: a toolkit for ontologies and text mining (2020) https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.02168
- » Acidoseq: studying Acidobacteria reads from a Nanopore metagenomic data (2018)
- » An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data (2018) https://doi.org/10.1101/288969

Interests

I enjoy a wide variety of activities in my spare time; I enjoy creative hobbies/crafts: pottery, sewing, and knitting. I like to spend my time developing my knowledge and working on personal projects - these can be found in my GitHub portfolio; with blogs discussing some of these projects can be found in my personal site here: https://sap218.github.io/.